# **ANDY ESKRIDGE**

850.341.9336 | andy@eskridge.dev | eskridge.dev | Dallas, TX

#### SENIOR TECHNOLOGY LEADER

Senior Technology Leader with experience managing product development, software engineering and quality assurance teams. Produces highly productive and effective teams through technological expertise and empathetic leadership, building value through trust and personal investment in team members. Success in managing growing markets, delivering multiple products, and producing impressive results on time. Can take complete ownership of the design, development, testing, deployment, and maintenance of software applications, systems, and technology projects.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## CENERGISTIC | DALLAS, TX Chief Technical Officer

2018-2022 2021-2022

- Created products that doubled the amount of square footage our employees could manage, increasing by multiple million square feet
- Led training sessions for the company and for users of up to 150 people
- Worked with operations, marketing, and other departments to align technology with the company's goals
- Managed the corporate strategic roadmap across multiple products and guided the leadership team on what products and features should be prioritized
- Provided opportunities for members of the team to grow in their careers and stretch their skills, leading to their promotions
- Able to quickly pivot and extend products to allow Cenergistic to expand into new markets
- Head of the IT department and managed the transition from in-house IT employees to a Managed Service Provider

## **Director of Software Development**

2018-2021

- Built out a team of developers and QA within six months of starting
- Managed a team of ten reports
- Shifted infrastructure from bare virtual machines to containerized applications hosted on AWS Elastic Container Service reducing costs by 50%
- Reviewed developer code and provided kind feedback to help teach and improve our product
- Created a web scrapping platform that scaled out extremely well via AWS Fargate that allowed the company to obtain interval data from utility companies

# BECK TECHNOLOGY | DALLAS, TX Project Leader

2016-2018

#### i roject Leader

- Lead and trained a team of two junior developers
- Developed user stories and worked through the implementation with my team
- Implemented a cloud-based 3D model viewer into the desktop application
- Created a 3D model comparison tool to compare multiple versions of a model

## PROVIDER SCIENCE | DALLAS, TX

2015-2016

### **Senior Software Engineer**

- Designed and implemented a prediction system capable of determining the optimal number of personnel needed to staff a pharmacy
- Engineered the Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) process data flow that provided raw data to the prediction system
- Developed a simple user experience that automated the ETL process for users, enabling them to simply drag and drop data into a SFTP site

# GWYNN GROUP | DALLAS, TX Senior Software Engineer

2015-2015

- Created a forecast engine that could predict any time-series metric
- The forecast engine reduced false alarms by 20% compared to the other forecast algorithms that were used
- Designed and implemented many custom visualizations utilizing D3 to help clients understand and explore extremely large datasets

ALLEGRO | DALLAS, TX 2013-2015 Software Engineer

- Rewrote the build process using MSBuild and C#. This resulted in a speed up of the build time by four times, going from hours to minutes.
- Used the speed and reliability of the new build process to impact the software development cycle, enabling more integration builds and greater product reliability
- Developed new Business Intelligence Portal using C#, MVC5, and SQL Server
- Created over twenty BI reports using Tableau

## **Technologies and Tools**

AWS, Typescript, React, React Native, SQL, Python, Java, Docker, Terraform, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Redis, Elasticsearch, Postman, Cypress, Puppeteer, .NET, C#, D3, Fastlane, TestFlight, Sentry, VSCode, GitHub, GitHub Actions, and JIRA

#### **EDUCATION**

Computer Science, University of Texas, Austin, TX

2012